







Team Lead seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, ASP. Net

MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Bootstrap, Agile, HTML, CSS, C#, WebAPI,

LINQ, SQLServer, NUnit Testing, jasmine Unit Testing.

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Team Lead/Tech Lead, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, ASP. Net MVC, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Bootstrap, Agile, HTML, CSS, C#, WebAPI, LINQ, SQLServer, NUnit

Testing, jasmine Unit Testing.

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

9.7 years of IT experience with proven success in Analysis, Design, Development, Implementation, Deployment and Testing of various object-oriented Intranet, Client-Server multi-tier Web Based applications

Hands-on experience in developing web-based applications using ASP.NET, ASP.NET M/C, Typescript, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML.

Experience in creating a RESTful Web API service using ASP.NET Web API to generate data, which was then consumed in the front-end by Telerik kendo controls.

Excellent experience in Web API in cross domain environment and other .NET technologies including Entity Framework and LINO

Experience in unit testing frameworks such as Jasmine, NUnit.

Experience in implementing ASP.NET server controls, Ajax, Microsoft Ajax Toolkit and Log4Net in ASP.Net applications.Worked extensively with Data Adapter, Dataset, Data reader as a part of ADO.NET to access and update database.

Work Experience

Accenture Services Pvt. Ltd as Application Development Team Lead Jul 2015 to Aug 2020

Description

The performance of the production system can be measured and improved based on constraints and operating envelopes. Any deviation between the expectation and the actual system performance can be derived from these limits. The Smart Limit Store is introduced as a tactical solution to store these limits, performance curves and envelopes. The purpose of this integrated Limit Store is to become the single central repository as part of the PTMIT Tools for limits, curves and envelopes. This will bring the advantages of consistency of storage, definition and representation of limits.

Responsibilities

- Developed ASP.NET M/C application using C#.Net and Kendo Controls.
- Integrated JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript and AJAX to provide rich web end-user experiences.
- Used the database first approach with the Entity Framework to generate models and the DBContext.
- Created a RESTful Web API service using ASP.NET Web API to generate data, which was then consumed in the front-end by Telerik kendo controls
- Used Postman to test Web API functionality.
- Implemented CRUD operations using \$http service to call Web API methods.
- Implemented unit testing using Jasmine throughout the project.
- Debugging of UI code using browser tools such as developer console in various browsers.
- Worked as a Quality Lead to maintain the application standards, code reviews, code coverage and monitoring and fix the quality issues Used Agile/Scrum software development methodology
- Provided the solution direction for the Product Backlogs and bugs and helped to team in resolving technical issues.
- Used TFS for code management and version control

Technologies: NET 4.0, ASP:NET M/C, TypeScript, C#, Web API, MS SQL Server, Entity Framework, jQuery, JSON, TFS.

Hibernia Networks Pvt. Ltd as Dotnet Developer Dec 2013 to Jul 2015

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Description

A Hibernia network is a high end internet service provider for some of the world's largest internet based companies in Europe, USA & Asia. The Pricing tool application allows Hibernia administrators to manage on-net and off-net services. On-net service provides Hibernia networks owned connectivity to clients. Off-net services are purchased by Hibernia and then use self-grid to provide end connections to customer. Application includes product configuration & pricing strategy, customer management including geography and routing optimization, vendor management, reports and other admin activities.

Responsibilities

- Involved in development of web based applications, classes using ASP M/C that incorporates both N-tier architecture and database connectivity.
- Implemented client side validations using JQuery and ASP.NET MVC Validation at Controller level.
- Developed complex MVC Controller, View Models and Helper methods linked to backend database.
- Developed Data Access Layers using ADO.net Entity Frame Work and LINQ to SQL.
- Good experience in implementation of Log4Net.
- Involved in Unit Testing of the entire application...

SRA Systems Ltd as Executive

Jul 2012 to Nov 2013

Description

Online Catalog System is an e-commerce portal where in customers can view the various products in the portal and can place orders in it.Description

Online Catalog System is an e-commerce portal where in customers can view the various products in the portal and can place orders in it. This web application contains modules like display of products based on catalogs, categories and themes. This also contains online orders, online quotations that helps the customer to negotiate price and place orders. Any end users who visit the portal can also register themselves to become customers. Customers can login to view their purchase profiles, invoices, quotations, back orders and existing open orders.

Responsibilities

- involved in development of web based applications, classes using ASP M/C that incorporates both N-tier architecture and database connectivity.
- Retrieving data using LINQ to SQL with ASP.NET, worked with the database using LINQ to SQL.
- Optimized the application, fine tuning the script on client resulted in great performance improvement.
- Implemented client side validations using JQuery and ASP.NET IMC Validation at Controller level.
- Designed static and dynamic pages for modules.
- Created resource file for the site.
- Used third party tool for generating the reports. Implemented version controlling using SVN.
- Involved in Unit Testing of the entire application

This web application contains modules like display of products based on catalogs, categories and themes. This also contains online orders, online quotations that helps the customer to negotiate price and place orders. Any end users who visit the portal can also register themselves to become customers. Customers can login to view their purchase profiles, invoices, quotations, back orders and existing open orders.

Responsibilities

- involved in development of web based applications, classes using ASP M/C that incorporates both N-tier architecture and database connectivity.
- Retrieving data using LINQ to SQL with ASP.NET, worked with the database using LINQ to SQL.
- Optimized the application, fine tuning the script on client resulted in great performance improvement.
- Implemented client side validations using JQuery and ASP.NET M/C Validation at Controller level.
- Designed static and dynamic pages for modules.
- Created resource file for the site.
- Used third party tool for generating the reports.
- Implemented version controlling using SVN.
- Involved in Unit Testing of the entire application.

Technologies: .NET 4.0, ASP.NET M/C, C#, WCF, MS SQL Server, JQuery, JSON, CSS, SVN.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from acharya nagarjuna university in 2005

PG: MCA (Computers) from Anna University, Chennai in 2008

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Microsoft .Net Framework, C#.Net,		
ASP.NET Web Form, ASP.NET MVC		
LINQ, Odata, ADO.NET, Entity Framework		
Typescript, jQuery, Knockout JS		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Bootstrap, HTML, Microsoft SQL Server		
TFS, CI/CD, Sonarqube, Agile		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English					

Į.		
Telugu		
relugu		

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.